riya.travel 2012-05-31

# Privacy Policy

|  |  Privacy Policy 

As a registered member of [WWW.RIYA.TRAVEL](http://www.riya.travel/), you will be entitled to savings and benefits on airfares, hotel reservations, holiday packages and car rentals, among other travel services. In addition, look forward to receiving monthly newsletters and exclusive promotions offering special deals.

That's why we've provided this Privacy Policy, which sets forth our policies regarding the collection, use and protection of the personal information of those using the [www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) website. Personal information means information that can be linked to a specific individual, such as name, address, telephone number, e - mail address, and credit card number. 

We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy, and become familiar with it, but you should know that we do not sell or rent our customers' personal information to third parties. 

Please note that we review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to make sure you have the latest version. Regardless of later updates, we will abide by the privacy practices described to you in this Privacy Policy at the time you provided us with your personal information.

In this Privacy Policy, terms that commence with a capital letter are defined in this Section or in the preamble. 

"Guest"  means an individual who can search and book Products or Services on the Site without being a Member. 

"Member"  means an individual who has registered with the Site. Members choose a Member ID and a password. 

"Member Id"  means the e-mail address you use (with your password) to login to our Site. 

"Riya"  or "we"  means Riya, INC and its subsidiaries and affiliates. 

"Personal Information"  means any information, recorded in any form, about an identified individual, or an individual whose identity may be inferred from the information. This includes, for example, name, e-mail and mailing address, telephone number, billing and account information and other information incidental to providing Products or Services (including information about individuals traveling with you). 

"Products or Services"  means the airline travel, hotel accommodation, car rental, ground transportation, tours, theater tickets, and attractions, travel insurance and other items available from the Site. 

to "Book"  means to reserve 

"Session Data"  means usage information, such as the type of Internet browser and operating system an individual uses, the domain name of the site from which the individual came, the date, time and duration of the visit, number of visits, average time spent on the individual's site, pages viewed, domain name of the individual and number of cookies accumulated. 

"Site"  means the [www.riya.com](http://www.riya.com/) site and its respective sub sites together with the respective content, Products and Services available from this sites or sub sites. 

"Subscriber"  means an individual who elects to receive offers or promotions from Riya without becoming a Member or a Guest. 

BY SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, AND/OR BY USING OUR SITE, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW. 

If you do not agree with these terms, do not provide any Personal Information to us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personal Information, we may not be able to provide you with Products or Services that can be offered on our Site only if we have access to certain Personal Information. 

Minors 

Minors (as defined under the laws of their jurisdiction or residence) are not eligible to register for, use or Book the Products or Services available on our Site. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from any Minor, and will not use this information if we discover that it has been provided by a Minor 

Other Travelers or Contacts 

If you Book Products or Services for other travelers using your Member ID and password, or if you provide us with contact information of a third party for Riya Alerts, you must make sure that you have the right to do so. By providing the Personal Information of another traveler, you represent that you have all necessary authority and/or have obtained all necessary consents from such person to enable us to collect, use and disclose his or her Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

3\. What Personal Information we collect 

We collect only such information as necessary to provide Products and Services to you. 

When you are just visiting 

You can visit certain areas of our Site without revealing who you are or signing-in.

When you visit our Site as a Guest, Member or Subscriber, we collect Session Data through Cookies. 

When you register as a Member 

If you register with us as a Member, we collect Personal Information that is necessary to provide the Products and Services offered on our Site. We require that you provide your name and e-mail address. You also need to choose a password, which will be required to gain access to portions of our Site reserved for Member use. We might also request your home zip code. 

You may elect to provide other information, for example, gender, activities and lifestyle preferences or preferred destinations. 

When you Book Products or Services as a Member 

When you Book Products or Services from our Site as a Member, you must provide payment or other necessary information. This includes, for example, billing information, driver information or similar information as required by the travel service provider(s). 

When you Book Products or Services for a third party 

When you Book Products or Services for a third party using your Member ID and password, we will collect that third party's name and contact information, and other information as required by the travel service provider(s), so that we can complete the booking. 

When you use the Site as a "Guest" 

If you are not a Member, you may elect to use our Site as a Guest. If you Book Products or Services as a Guest, you must provide Personal Information to complete the booking (for example name, phone number or billing information) as required by the travel service provider(s). You must also provide an e-mail address so that we can send you our welcome e-mail and a confirmation of the Book. With the confirmation, we will provide you with a temporary password so that you can return to the Site if you wish to review information about your Book. 

When you "Subscribe"

When you become a Subscriber, we collect your name and e-mail address, so that you may receive offers or promotions from Riya without becoming a Member or Guest. 

When you participate in contests, promotions, raffles, or sweepstakes 

We may offer you the chance to win a variety of travel related prizes by sponsoring contests, promotions, raffles or sweepstakes. If you choose to participate, we will collect Personal Information such as your full name, e-mail address or mailing address. 

If a third party administers the contest, your participation may be subject to additional terms and conditions and that third party's privacy policy. We are not responsible for such third parties. You should carefully review these third parties' terms and conditions. 

When you participate in a survey or a focus group

From time to time, we may invite you to participate in a survey or a focus group. You are free to participate or not. We will collect the responses you provide, and will make them anonymous to aggregate them with those of other participants. If you use a bulletin board, blog, or chat room on this Site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums. 

When we advertise on third party sites 

When you visit a site on which we advertise and click through our advertisement, we may place cookies on your computer. The information that we collect through this technology is not personally identifiable.

When you call or write to our Customer Service 

When you call or write to our Customer Service, we collect contact information (for example name, phone number, mailing address or e-mail address) and information about the relevant Book as necessary to assist you. For example, if you call for assistance with a preexisting Book, or to make a Book, we may request your contact and billing information

When we send e-mails or e-newsletters 

When we send e-mails or e-newsletters, or when you forward a promotion or search results to a third party using the "Tell a Friend" feature insert a in the e-mail. Our “Tell a Friend” feature works in the following areas:

• If you tell a friend about a promotion or a flight that you found on our Site, a one-time email will be sent to your friend about this information. In these instances we do not store any of the names or email addresses of your friends.

• If you tell a friend about an itinerary that you booked through our Site, we will send your friend a one-time email with the requested information. In this instance we do not permanently store the names and email addresses of your friends and do not use that data for any additional marketing purposes.

Supplementation of Information 

In order to provide certain services to you, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submitted to us with information from third party sources:

• Address Verification: : If you book travel or other products or services from us, we use third parties in order to verify your address information during the credit card authorization process. 

• Enhancement of Profile Information:  We book marketing data from third parties and add it to our existing user database, to better target our advertising and to provide pertinent offers in which we think you would be interested. To enrich our profiles of individual customers, we tie this information to the personally identifiable information they have provided to us.

4\. How we use the information we collect 

• To record your travel preferences, to make reservations or to communicate with you about your travel plans

• To issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments:

• To provide tips or guidance on how to use our Site, inform you of new features on our Site or provide other information that may be of interest to users:

Contests - Promotions - Raffles - Sweepstakes

If you participate in a contest, promotion, raffle or sweepstakes, we will only use your Personal Information to notify you if you win.

We may send you additional communications only if you have specifically requested to receive our newsletters, e-mails, personalized offers or other promotional materials when filling out the contest or promotion form.

We will share the information with the entities with which we may have teamed to propose the joint promotion.

Session Data

We use Session Data, collected through cookies, to better understand how our Site is navigated, how many visitors arrive at specific pages, the length and frequency of stays at our Site, the variety of searches of our Site's database, the types of browsers and computer operating systems used by our visitors and the Internet Protocol addresses from which visitors connect to our Site. 

We also use this information to improve our Site content and ease of use, to personalize and improve your individual viewing experiences on our Site and provide information that may be of interest to you.

Aggregated Information

Aggregated information is information recorded in any form about more than one individual, where the identity of the individual is not known and cannot be inferred from the information. We may use aggregated information to describe our user base to current or potential partner’s investors and advertisers; after a survey, to understand and respond to market needs and preferences; or to make recommendations to other users of our Site. For example, if users of our Site who have traveled to a particular destination told us that they had positive experiences at a hotel in that destination, we might recommend that hotel.

What we do NOT do

We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, Member ID, login password or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.

Identity theft and the practice currently known as "phishing" are of great concern to us. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is our priority. For more information about phishing, you may want to visit the Federal Trade Commission at [www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/consumer/alerts/alt127.shtm](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/consumer/alerts/alt127.shtm)

5\. To whom we disclose Personal Information 

From time to time, we may disclose your Personal Information as follows:

• To those travel service providers with which you make arrangements through our Site, for example airlines, car rental, hotel, ground transportation, theater, attraction or travel insurance. We provide them with the Personal Information needed to make and complete the booking or reservation.

• To organizations that perform services for or on behalf of Riya, for example to provide customer service, deliver tickets, ship items, process credit cards, for research, marketing, data processing, to measure the use of our Site, to facilitate usage by a visitor or to offer credit card services or evaluate your creditworthiness. We will share with these companies only that Personal Information which they need to work on our behalf. Some of these service providers may be located in countries outside the US and outside the European Economic Area ("EEA").Your Personal Information will be provided to these organizations only if they agree to use such information solely for the purpose of providing services to Riya, and under the instructions of Riya, and with respect to that information, to act in a manner consistent with the relevant principles articulated in this Policy. By submitting your personal data, you agree to the transfer, storing and processing of your data outside the US and outside the EEA.

• We may collaborate with other companies to offer you additional Products or Services, for example, through sweepstakes, raffles and promotions. We will share Personal Information that is necessary for these other companies to provide the Products or Services that you have requested. This policy does not cover the use of your Personal Information by these other companies. We encourage you to read a company's privacy policy before requesting any of its products or services.

• To protect our Site and our rights under our Terms and Conditions of Use; to protect ourselves against liability or prevent fraudulent activity; or where it is necessary to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain.

• To effect a corporate transaction, in connection with the sale, merger, spin-off or other corporate reorganization of our corporation, where the information is provided to the new controlling entity in regular course of business.

• Where the information is public.

• To our insurers and to regulatory agencies.

Disclosure without consent

Please note that there are circumstances where the use or disclosure of Personal Information may be justified or permitted, or where Riya may be obligated to disclose information without consent. Such circumstances may include:

• If required to comply with a subpoena or warrant issued or an order made by a court, person or body with jurisdiction to compel the production of information or to comply with the rules or court relating to the production of records.

If we receive a formal request to disclose your Personal Information in connection with a legal action, we will attempt to contact you about it, if permitted by law, via the e-mail address you provided during registration, before we respond to that request.

• If we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it.

• To a person who needs the information because of an emergency that threatens the life, health or security of an identifiable person or group.

• Where it is necessary to collect monies owing to us.

National Security 

In order to protect national security and to ensure travel security, the United States Government and other governments may request access to passenger name records, which typically includes name, flight origin, flight destination, flight time, duration of flight, seat location, travel agent, form of payment, credit card numbers, travel itinerary, address, telephone number and meal requests. In response to such request, Riya and/or its providers will give access to all the information you provide at the time of making your reservation to the applicable government agencies of the countries to or from which you are traveling.

Retention and storage

We will retain your Personal Information in our databases in accordance with our Records Management Policy and applicable laws. This period may extend beyond the end of your relationship with us, but it will be only as long as it is necessary for us to have sufficient information to respond to any issues that may arise later. For example, we may need or be required to retain information to allow you to obtain credit for a trip you Booked but had to cancel. We may also need to retain certain information to prevent fraudulent activity; to protect ourselves against liability, permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain; or if we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it.

Your Personal Information will be stored in secured locations and on servers controlled by Riya, located either at our offices or at the offices of our service providers as described in How we protect Personal Information.

6\. How we protect Personal Information 

Riya employs physical, administrative and technical safeguards to help protect the confidentiality and integrity of Personal Information and to reduce the risk of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or modification of Personal Information. When Personal Information is sent to our service providers, we require in our contracts with them that they protect all Personal Information in a manner consistent with the principles articulated in this Privacy Policy.

If you choose to contact Riya through the Site, you should be aware that any information transmitted electronically via the World Wide Web might not be secure. Riya assumes no liability for the loss of any information that you transmit to us via the World Wide Web. However, should you choose to pay by credit card when making a booking, reservation or book on the Site, your card details are encrypted for the transaction.

In communicating with you, we may send e-mail as unencrypted plain text because we are aware that most Members, Guests or Subscribers cannot readily process encrypted e-mail. This is done for your convenience, but with the security concern that, if misrouted or intercepted, it could be read more easily than encrypted e-mail.

7\. HOW YOU CAN OPT-OUT OF RECEIVING OUR PROMOTIONAL E-MAILS?

At any time, you may unsubscribe from our Real Deals, Insider, or other newsletter or similar services through the "My Account" link on the [www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) Site home page. As a member or promotion/sweepstakes entrant, you will occasionally receive e-mail updates from us about fare sales in your area, special offers, new [www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) services, and other noteworthy items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative. Of course, if you would rather not receive them, please click on the "unsubscribe" link or follow the instructions in each e - mail message or send us an email info.usa@Riyagroup.Travel. 

[www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) reserves the right to limit membership to those who will accept e - mails. Members will be notified via e - mail prior to any actions taken.

8\. WHAT OTHER INFORMATION SHOULD I KNOW ABOUT MY PRIVACY? 

[www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) site contains links to other web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another web site for which [www.riya.travel.com](http://www.riya.travel/) has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from this Privacy Policy. Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords, and your[www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) site membership account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you're online.

In addition to the circumstances described above, [www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) may disclose the[www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/)site member information if required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of[www.riya.com](http://www.riya.travel/) or any or all of its affiliates, associates, employees, directors or officers or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities. In addition, if[www.riya.travel.com](http://www.riya.travel/)or substantially all of its assets are acquired, our customer information will most likely also be transferred in connection with such acquisition

This policy is effective as of October 1, 2009. Any material changes in the way [www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/)uses personal information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Statement. Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Statement or our privacy practices via email to info.usa@Riyagroup.Travel. Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. [www.riya.travel](http://www.riya.travel/) will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries within five business days of receipt.

Monitoring 

Riya may from time to time monitor and review any information transmitted or received through the Site, or through telephone or email communications, for quality assurance and other purposes. We reserve the right to censor, edit, remove or prohibit the transmission or receipt of any information that Riya deems inappropriate or in violation of these Terms and Conditions. During monitoring the information may be examined, recorded or copied.

9\. Changes to the Privacy Policy 

Changes to the Privacy Policy and Changes in Ownership 

We may change or supplement this Privacy Policy from time to time. We may also undergo a change of ownership. Privacy Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date we post the revised Privacy Policy to the Site, as well as to existing information held by us.

If we decide to change this policy in a material way, we will obtain the necessary consents required under applicable privacy laws if we seek to collect, use or disclose Personal Information for purposes other than those to which consent has been obtained, unless otherwise required or permitted by law. If any proposed change is unacceptable to you, you may request that we close your account.  
  
---|---
